# DMITRY KALINCHENKO

Phone: 734.834.1395 E-Mail: Dmitry.kalinchenko@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dkalinchenko

#### SUMMARY

Management consultant and project manager with experience working for Fortune 100 companies in a diverse set of industries. Graduate degree from top-tier university. Experience with software development as both a developer and PM. Solid project management, market research, verbal and written communication and relationship building skills.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

**Project Management:** 3 years of experience guiding projects from inception through completion. 6 years of experience of building relationships, presenting cases, and conducting brainstorming sessions with senior executives of large organizations.

Market Research & Sizing: 5 years of experience doing market research, forecasting and sizing studies the service of setting the market context for a new opportunity. Developed Excel-based models to project growth and estimate the future market.

**Primary Research & Voice of the Customer:** 5 years of experience identifying, recruiting, interviewing and synthesizing insights from dozens of individuals for every project. Wide range of industry experience from consumer goods to basic chemicals.

**Visual/Information Design:** 10+ years of experience designing visually compelling and complex charts, presentations, user interfaces, and marketing materials.

Web Development: Beginner to intermediate JavaScript and D3.js skills. Intermediate to advanced HTML and CSS.

Industry Experience: Technology, oil & gas, power & utilities, chemicals, basic materials, healthcare, education.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Consultant (March 2016 – Present) | Analyst (March 2014 – March 2016)

The Inovo Group | Ann Arbor, MI / Boulder, CO

Inovo is an innovation consulting firm specializing in working with clients in energy, chemical and material industries. As a consultant I manage initial pilots to mid-sized projects, perform market analysis and primary and secondary research in support of discovering of new strategic opportunities for our clients. Some notable accomplishments:

- Developed a framework for quick and effective market sizing studies
- Redesigned the structure of the Inovo's opportunity templates one of the centerpieces of Inovo's framework
- Redesigned the look and feel of the standard templates to make them more visually impactful and user-friendly

During my time with Inovo, I worked with companies like: ExxonMobil, Nestle Purina, Dow Chemical, Cargill, Lubrizol and other Fortune 100 companies.

## Project Manager Scrum Master (June 2013 – December 2013)

HookLogic, Inc | Ann Arbor, MI

At HookLogic, I was a Scrum Master facilitating Agile Scrum development process of a group of nine developers including ticket triaging and release QA testing. Some notable accomplishments:

- Developed UI mockups and scope document for a user-tracking system feature
- Cleaned up the scrum backlog from 100+ random tickets to a manageable dozen in order to provide a better understanding of team's performance

# Consultant (May 2012 - May 2013) | Business Analyst (September 2010 - May 2012)

Enovio Consulting | Ann Arbor, MI

At Enovio, I worked with a diverse set of clients on projects primarily focused on cost-cutting and change management in energy and education sector. Some notable accomplishments:

- Identified cost cutting initiatives resulting in 10% reduction of corporate operating budget for a utility company and developed a detailed implementation schedule of said initiatives.
- Identified and implemented annual savings of over 25% in resource selection and procurement strategy for a for-profit college without reducing the efficiency of business operations, resulting in over \$600,000 of cost reductions annually.
- Redesigned the internal corporate identity, including firm's logo, brochures and the website.

### **EDUCATION**

**University of Michigan, School of Information**, Ann Arbor, MI MS Information Science with Concentration in Information Economics

May 2012

**University of Michigan**, Ann Arbor, MI Dual BA in Economics and Sociology

May 2010

## **OTHER NOTABLE ACHIEVEMENTS**

Fluent in 2 languages English, Russian.

Competes in triathlons, marathons and adventure races.

Freelances as a graphic designer and web developer in my free time.